Miguel Monteiro Claveri

Software Engineer

Profile

25 years old Software Engineer motivated to learn new things everyday and ambitious to reach all my goals. I'm a self-organized, problem solver, agile & proactive person, I am eager to reach always my owns limits, define new ones and push towards self-improvement. I have a big desire to innovate and find new ways to do things.

Swiss residency permit B holder

Experience

IoT Software Engineer - BOBST

Lausanne, Switzerland

October 2020 - Current position

Developed "Bobst Connect", which is an IoT solution to monitor / orchestrate Bobst machines. Collaborated in a scrum based team where I managed to develop technical and soft skills.

I have mainly worked as a Full-stack developer which allowed me to improve my skill-set, from Angular and state-of-the-art web technologies, to .Net Azure server-less function apps for the backend.

Participated in architecture meetings, implemented new features, improved optimization of the application, bug fixing along with adding and maintaining tests in all the phases, to provide a stable and safe development environment with DevOps methodologies.

Technologies used: Angular / Typescript / Cypress - C# .NET - Azure web services

Full stack developer - Es Liceu coop

Mallorca, Spain

March 2020 - June 2020

Internship developing a web application for a school's students management.

Technologies used: VueJS - Java / Spring / Hibernate - Docker / Jenkins - Flutter

Education

Bachelor's degree - Techniques on Software Development

UOC

September 2023 - Current

Web Applications Development - Professional superior education degree

Es Liceu coop - September 2018 - June 2020

Graduated with high honors student

Data structures / algorithms / Web development / Java / Modern design patterns / Application deployments / Databases SQL & NOSQL

Projects & Awards

- Graduated with **High Honors** in my latest degree
- Erasmus internship in Turku, Finland. Organizing the infrastructure for an *IoT* project to monitor a big-scale factory
- React native project to read and register NFC tools w/ Firebase
- Treese APP project

I co-founded this project with another colleague, where we had to develop a full-scale application in less than 3 months, for our degree thesis project. This application, improved the productivity of the students during internships by 100% because we simplified the internship hours management and allowing the students have more time to focus in their thesis.

Technologies used: VueJS - Java / Spring / Hibernate - Docker / Jenkins - Material Design

Contact details

miguelmonteiroclaveri@gmail.com

+41 (0)76 779 22 98

Chemin de Bel-Orne 32D Prilly, 1008 Switzerland

Place of birth

Tarragona, Spain

Links

LinkedIn Github

Technical skills

Angular / TypeScript Java / Spring / Hibernate

C# / .Net

Clean code

JSON

REST API's

SASS / SCSS

Azure cloud & DevOps

CI / CD Pipelines

OOP

Algorithms & Data structures

Docker / Jenkins

GIT

Micro-services

TDD

UI / UX Developer

Soft skills

Analytical mindset

Cultural awareness

Solution oriented person

Aaile

Proactive

Ambitious

Good team worker

Independent

Spoken languages

Spanish Native
Portuguese Native
English C2
French B2